Raúl Calderón

Full Stack Developer

Raúl Francisco Calderón Rochín

Hermosillo Sonora, MX.

+52 644 143 9913
raul41092@gmail.com



About me

I'm a developer with almost 10 years of experience. I've been working remotely for many clients from Mexico and the United States. I know how to team work and I enjoy learning new technologies and new skills from the people around me.

Skills

HTML PHP

CSS PYTHON

BOOTSTRAP CMS (WORDPRESS/DRUPAL)

JAVASCRIPT MYSQL

AJAX GIT

JQUERY API/API RESTFUL

Work history

Powdevs - BillingTree | A REPAY Company / Full Stack Developer 2020 - 2024

- Supported and created new functionalities to a payment system used in many hospitals in the USA called "Ipayx".
- Participated in addressing and fixing problems or bugs caused in a production environment (such as duplicated payments, failed payments, etc.) using control versions.
- Optimized the generation of XML or PDF reports with the information of the daily, monthly or annually payments.
- Participated in creating and implementing new features like a two factor autenticator (2FA) for application logins and sessions.

Rivka Development - Sales Simplicity Software, Inc. / Full Stack Developer

2019 - 2020

- Supported and created new functionalities to a WordPress customized plugin known as "Options Online", which is used for many clients in the USA and allows dynamically to show the information of a website used to sell residential houses in the United States: Sales Simplicity.
- Developed and implemented XML scripts to export file reports with the sales and houses info (prices, availability, etc.).

Vagapp Soluciones / Full Stack Developer

2015 - 2019

- At charge of developing many projects for multiple clients, most of them in Mexico. Some of those projects were:
- WedProduction: A totally customized web page that was created in Drupal, which is used as a wedding social media, where you are allowed to quote, look for professionals, create events, etc.
- VisitMexico: A website that is used to see all the upcoming events in Mexico state.
- Arizona Driver Club (AZ Drivers): A web page that was given support in some functionalities, such as quote insurance for cars.

Education

Instituto Tecnológico de Sonora (ITSON) / Software Engineer

2011 - 2015

The career was completed in that period of time.

Languages

- Spanish (native)
- English (advanced)

Courses and Certificates

Certificated in "Creación de páginas web responsive con Bootstrap".

The course was taken on Udemy.

GIT CERTIFICATION...

The course was taken on Desafios Latam.

INTRODUCTION TO DATA ANALYSIS WITH PYTHON.

The course was taken on Udemy.

PYTHON FOR DATA SCIENCE - Machine Learning with Python.

The course was taken on Desafios Latam.

AI & ChatGPT From Zero to Advanced.

The course was taken on Udemy.